so go to the verses just above that
there's a few lines there you go
okay this is meditation number twelve
page six but don't look I want to talk
to you about it first okay
so this is what happens if you learn to
take refuge okay this is the Karma of
taking refuge properly okay
parting Jubilees young so there are many
versions of bois de boulogne the
perfection of wisdom and one is called
the brief perfection of wisdom parting
dupa okay and in some of them are 8,000
verses some of them are 12,000 verses
some of them are a hundred thousand
verses and some of them 15 I know anyway
cap song sanam subpoena comes from Dion
Newton and this is very very famous
quotation and it says if the Karma of
going for refuge properly was turned
into a physical thing like a piano or a
baseball or cactus okay if that karma
turned into a physical thing comes from
being near the tomb the universe
couldn't hold it there wouldn't be room
in the universe to fit it okay so it's
supposed to be that going for refuge
properly by you know thinking about the
husband who's not there okay going to
refuge for that protection that kind of
protection of not believing in that
husband who's not your fault okay that
karma if it became a physical thing it
couldn't fit in this universe okay then
he's going to talk about it
Shiva talk young dude check the opinions
on Cinnabar kidding me along with you so
what this is saying is that the good
things that happen to you
if you take refuge properly that good
seeds cannot be measured even by Buddha
cannot be measured okay cool cool stock
bar Sun gaining Shing champ are tender
some way especially Lord Buddha is such
a powerful object among the three three
work jewels among the three jewels
Buddha is so powerful that if you do
something towards the Buddha day like
chamber gets on that karma done towards
a person who is enlightened it doesn't
matter your motivation your motivation
can be lousy usually not motivation is
90% right but the Buddha is such a
powerful object that if you do anything
you know if you sneeze well towards the
Buddha you get you know you're rich for
many lifetimes it's okay like that okay
that's not because of you because of
them okay that object is so powerful we
talked about powerful objects mom dad
you know teachers people who need things
emergencies people who helped you and
people who help other people okay so
this is just one more young jokes on
topic your neighbor birthday so good
loan Nam talkie if you take refuge with
a good motivation
don't junk topic you remember don't they
that karma cannot go anyplace except to
make your Buddha okay if you take refuge
with good motivation okay then there's
no choice that karma will go to make
your Buddha you can't stop it okay then
he tells a story about that from ninja
Tama couple what's been a couple the
Lotus Sutra okay very famous right
there's a couple of Lotus Sutra but
they're all the same ones longer one
shorter okay by the way if you want to
be a vegetarian if you want to tell
Buddhist people they should be
vegetarian the Lotus Sutra is the is the
book to read
okay he makes a list of every known kind
of meat including human meat and he says
don't eat it okay so if someone tells
you British don't accept vegetarianism
you can read them the Lotus Sutra okay
so now he's going to quote the Lotus
Sutra Lord Buddha is talking to a nun
say Arnon don't say Ananda another means
unhappy person a nun that means very
happy person okay like our Mirta Amrita
means kills you very much okay America
means deafness you see long a means very
much short a means not not so when a
yoga teacher I'm in a yoga class and
teacher says let's do arm murder
I'm arm Rita like no no I don't want to
die okay all right come go Anandi very
happy person Ireland did thought a
burner so Buddha is talking to a number
and he says let me let me tell you
harness Kim docks in Beijing let's say
some guy is a farmer just normal person
and he's a farmer she told me Apple and
his field has no rocks in it and by the
way those of you who grew up Christian I
did still AM
there's a beautiful Jewish uses the same
language he has the same story okay
Kimber Shing doll the the field has no
more stones
don't doomed mapa there's no tree trunks
broken twinkle stumps David Toms and
Herman mapa
there's no thorns okay in that field
como mapa there's no gravel segment
member no pebbles son la terre the
ground is very fertile good soil
she kept accurately leg bone milk if
they plant if they plow the field
properly large a key chamber if they
work it properly they summon young
serpent if they place a fresh seed in it
which is poo source powerful okay say
labor and they plant at the right time
of year
okay long dong Lee Mayman apple if
they're not damaged if the seeds are not
damaged by the window and the Sun my
choppa is they don't get broken my
choppa if they don't get bruised my oppa
if they don't spoil chill my Supergirl
that seized power cannot go away cannot
disappear sobbing did our dude on six or
she locked up a if they plant those
seeds at the right time in the field to
do so chicha if they water them
regularly do so come and they let the
ground dry when it should dry okay don't
overwater Tom Jane Lane lapis only and
if they protect those fields from
squirrels and things like that
Cowell okay and then Buddha's talking to
Ananda another what do you think Kimber
Simba debut in Sigma later on Shinji to
do something and they the farmer walks
into the field where he put the seed
perfectly watered it perfectly
and weather's perfect no animals
everything's perfect
okay changing out into song they're
singing more Duke if he sits down and
faces those field okay k southern case
southern the majority case i'ma keep my
kitchen you see it don't be seen
and please don't grow okay all right
please don't grow I came my kitchen my
PLC and if you do grow don't open these
and don't open fruits okay now that
they're with me girl I don't want any
weep I don't want any rice okay game to
me good I don't need it
okay please don't grow guys come God a
genie under Sam I'm Nanda what do you
think killed doc Simba Dead Sea key
salmon day doc salmon Mayan burger on
because of the words of the farmer will
the seeds turn into Nazis soma something
damn Malak so I don't think so that's
another I don't I don't think so
they worship on my luck so oh you know
Sugata Oh Buddha no just because the
guys sit down until the seeds don't
deceive it's it's not going to make them
Nazis okay I don't think so ok God
she'll talk ever deliver my in burger on
nipple normally do pump sofa and then
Buddha as Ananda so will those seeds
grow into plants which make fruits or
make grain ok will it happen
Ananda says sorry is it the case that by
the farmers words the plants will refuse
to grow fruits or refuse to grow rice or
if used to grow we you know it is
possible Tom them day my luck that's not
the case ok
Oh Buddha that's not the case
they worship on my laksa Sugata it's not
the way it is okay
the farmers words can't stop them okay
go
God seppuku God a disciple are 13c like
our son Gail are you including even if
okay Ananda even if a person is attached
to this life and even if a person
believes that this life is so nice so
cool but they make an offering to the
Buddha okay meaning to a powerful object
right Pune no need our cheek mark your
cheek and if they make a prayer when
they make the offering to the Buddha
like I'll offer a Buddha a cup of nice
teeth and say Buddha I offer you this
tea may I not reach nirvana
okay may I not remember please okay I
offer you this tea but I don't want to
lose the bother okay my guilty day case
a young dancing on the darling do admit
it's impossible that they won't reach
their money okay because they offered a
key to a wholly-owned thing highest
subject okay all right even if they'd
say please don't let me reach nirvana
they were recent of honor okay nothing
can stop it go cup man means go cup man
means no possibility 0% chance that they
won't reach nirvana
okay 0% chance okay cool go
oh I'm nan de san gil Akira gateway so
again I'm in do Kyung so if you take
refuge properly this is from the Lotus
Sutra the Lotus Sutra is a basis for
whole religions in Japan for example
nam-myoho-renge-kyo you know this thing
they beat the job and they walk around I
did it for a couple months
it's from it's just the first line of
the lowest Sutra that's their whole
religion millions of people okay
Sutra okay kongou sangee like a big area
our data min young ananda even if a
person doesn't want to be a Buddha gaben
young and a defiant day because of that
action taking refuge properly they will
become a Buddha nobody can stop it okay
come on young and they did it by do your
normal normal means
take my word fun okay nam OU höhle take
my word fun okay cool Buddha Buddhist
hit that okay take my word for it okay
JJ Samba song a chum the de la 17 K KP
kirisawa
if you just think about refuge correctly
once date on take a dip on young and the
dapper gent a you will get the result of
enlightened and nobody can stop it okay
mom owl take it from me that's what I
say who Buddha
okay Buddha said that take refuge
properly second husband refuge okay
forget the three jewels second husband
refuge take it correctly the karma is
the biggest comment you can make it's
cool because you really understand the
Buddha okay God is then I get this
argument you know people tell me oh I
was reading the bhagavad-gita you know
and in the Bhagavad Gita Krishna tells
Krishna should be cursed oh by the way
Kershner tells Arjuna don't be attached
to the fruits of your coma okay just do
nice things for people don't expect to
get good health or financial
independence or good relationships okay
don't don't think like that just do good
things and and don't worry about the
result okay and and there's a tradition
like that in America
so I don't know about China just do nice
things
don't worry what's going to come back to
you okay and that's okay that's okay
that kind of thinking is good but you
can't stop it okay it will chase you the
money will chase you the relationships
will chase you you know the good health
will chase you you can't escape you
can't say I don't want that result okay
if you plant a comma you can be a nice
person you can say you know I don't need
to be richer
I'm not doing this because I want to get
richer I'm not doing this because I want
my husband to be nice to me I'm just
doing it because I want to be a nice
person you can say that it's okay but
you can't stop the Karma it will chase
you it will run after you and catch you
the example I like to give is you know
30 years I helped this project with my
salary 19 years in the diamond business
I used a lot of my salaries for the
ancient books then I quit the diamond
business and did a three-year retreat
then when I came out I went to yoga at
Donnell interests and some guy came up
to me and hand me an envelope I don't
know this guy I never met this guy
inside the envelope there's a hundred
thousand dollar check it made the water
system that you're using we used it for
the water system you're using all of you
okay it just chases you okay you go to a
yoga class the money will come you can't
avoid it you know you can you can say I
don't want the seed to grow but it will
grow okay so meditation number twelve
page number six what's the name of the
meditation
and what's the name of the meditation
even if you ask it not to grow okay
so during this meditation you you have
to think about the Karma
okay of usually the fourth death okay
Gooding in the habit of achieving the
goals you want and getting the new habit
of stopping the problems you don't want
by using four steps right getting in
that habit is when you call self
perpetuating come on it just gets bigger
and bigger okay the more you use it the
more you want to use it you see what I
mean that you use it once you make the
Karma to use it again you use it again
you make the carmody use it twice you'd
use it again you make the current news
at four times and then that special
clamor of understanding where things
come from tends to perpetuate itself
like the Wheel of Life
four negative things okay the Wheel of
Life makes negative things tools for aid
sixteen using taking refuge by using
seeds to reach the goals in your life
okay tends to multiply upon itself okay
it's like double it goes like this
exponential you know it you use it once
suddenly you're using it half the day
suddenly you're using it every day
suddenly you're dreaming about it okay
it's just weird it's a wood climber it's
a cool Karma
okay and you can see I'm tired of
thinking about seeds I want to do
something without sneeze you can't okay
okay once you get into it once you see
how cool it is and all the weird things
happen to supernatural things
supernatural happy things what do we
call it in mixed nuts groups
you start to unreasonably happy it's
because this karma texture when you call
it not just multiply you know
exponentially increasing if you just try
it a few times it will take over your
life okay and then you can see I don't
want to be happy I don't want to have
finances I don't want to meet new
beautiful people I don't want to live in
a bubble where they put me in the top of
the couch on hotel with the best rock
and roll band in Asia you know I'm sorry
you'll have to go there okay got it cool
okay so when you did that meditation
just think about that you cannot escape
what's that expression in English you
can run but you can't hide there's an
English idiom you can run but you cannot
hide the money will find you then the
friends will find you okay the success
will find you okay sorry
that's a beautiful meditation all right
number 13 I'm not going to explain much
we have 27 to go I mean 27 total to do
we're only halfway through it you're
starting tomorrow evening number 13 is
basically week I was the guy with the
umbrella
somebody tell me nah
protection from huge mess-ups Adam kata
in the past okay
protection from huge boo-boos you may
when I mean most of my boobs I made when
I was seventeen I don't know what it is
they were all packed into one year in in
college okay okay that was the umbrella
guy what meditation repent 11 okay 13 is
almost the same okay
13 means bad stuff that's going to
happen to you okay bad stuff it's going
to happen to you right now in the next
few weeks okay like it didn't come from
20 years ago it came from last week okay
just steady slow bad crowd coming to you
okay
some crappy atrocities that kind of
day-to-day crap okay excuse me but it's
a good word that kind of bad things
can't touch you if you're taking refuge
regularly if you under if you're using
just using the four steps it gives you
your goals but it has a side effect it
infects the rest of your Karma's even
you're a media console so things you did
last week don't record and you just we
talked about it in DC I you know just
weird stuff happens to us we live in
this bubble you know somebody sent a
Bentley to pick a song and you know I
was telling Nick Nick somebody sent a
Bentley to pick me up and says well
geshe-la they did a program in a
different city that night he says we
went in a Rolls Royce
I'm like you know right yeah I didn't
get a Rolls Royces
yeah saved its life okay okay so mmm
this one is immediate promise okay
won't mess with you you know subway
breakdowns stuff like that okay like no
just just when you get out of the
subways and stops when you get to the
three jewels stuff like that immediate
unhappy things untouchable means and the
word in Tibetan is untouchable they
cannot touch you
that who's the last people of Buddha met
before I became enlightened yeah demons
what they do they truce to us and they
shot arrows at him because they were
upset they saw he's about to get
enlightened and they're like we gotta
get to the Buddha g.y right now just
don't take two arrows picture Spears why
he's gonna get in right we got a
destructive you know and they ran to the
Buddha gene i i sat there ones it's cool
and they put their arrows and they threw
their spears the girls took off their
clothes you know and the years turned
into flowers in the air and the arrows
turned into flowers and they just come
down flower you know and anybody came
enlightened okay so this is number 13
think about the problems you have I
don't know legal problems tax problems
wife problems you know rent problems job
problems and if you take refuge use
refuge to deal with your problems and
then it's like armor that the problems
come and they like doing be
okay they just go bumping and they don't
touch you they can't hurt you yes sir
Jerome yeah it helps too yeah if you
think about the four powers let's say I
lied to people right so what's the
what's the actual antidote what's the
third of the four powers huh make a
promise not to do it again okay
and what's the fourth do the opposite
you see number 3 is a negative promise I
won't do it again number 4 is a positive
promise I promise to do the opposite for
a while
I'll tell absolute truth to everybody I
don't like your dress today not the
whole truth okay but if you think about
it that's the same as dream you if you
do the four steps it's the same as the
four cars that's the point okay it's the
thing you know we struggle with that in
DC I you know do we tell them the four
powers or we just tell them the four
steps again I don't make enough money do
we tell them use the four powers to
remove your negative seeds or do we tell
them share things with other people the
positive one is more fits people most
people prefer to share things with
others to fix their poverty than to beat
themselves up for six weeks about how
cheap they were got it so when you're
teaching people you can teach them the
four powers which we do but that's
emphasis is negative you know you're a
bad person
you're collected bad seeds you're poor
you don't have enough money it's because
you were mean to other people
go go home and confess okay or you know
now what you have anything you get
please share it with other people and
then that that also asked to purify
because it's got number four its power
number four yeah but the one that
creates a new good seed also stops the
old bad seeds of ripening that's what we
talked about this morning you see so you
killed you feed two fish with one word
no that's not vegetarian okay okay so
we're finished number thirteen so I'd
like to do a meditation you ready we're
going to do meditation and we'll go
through the back up after the three-day
retreat I'll read you the scripture you
can fall asleep
and
check your phone
[Music]
blow your nose they want Cher
you can play horn on our next point
[Music]
okay and then get saddled closer eyes
don't get jet lag
I mean action my little smile relax your
eyes give up all the stuff you're
thinking about you can you can do it
later it will wait for you relax your
shoulders relax your fingers try to just
enjoy and give up all your worries all
your plans you can take care of them
later they never stop
you will die before they stop
take a Dharma break
check in with your teacher go to the
middle of your heart go deep down like
you dive into a pool and you're you're
underwater and you're going down down
down into your heart and you meet your
brill
your teacher down there inside a grain
of sugar you it gets just big enough to
fit both of you in a grain of sugar sit
with them girl quiet you're inside your
heart sit with them inside a grain of
sugar clear
take a moment to settle down and connect
with your teacher
now I'd like to think I asked you to
think of one of the most frightening
times of your life Hector told me a
story about he was in retreat recently
far away from other people and he was
bitten by a scorpion and he thought it
might be the kind that kills you and so
he he had a strange experience where he
had like a half hour or an hour and he
thought it's very possible he will die
within that half hour it's too far away
for other people to help him and just
think of something like that some
situation in your life which was
hopeless and dangerous myself I remember
I was on a plane and they told us that
the landing gear was not working and we
might die and so I think of a most
terrible moment in your life most sad
moment most dangerous moment the moment
when you were most having despair and
you you thought everything was
impossible
try to remember a moment like that
in the long room instruction for those
moments usually you're too scared to
think deeply about emptiness or there's
no time the plane is falling you have a
few minutes left
after the Scorpion value and it's very
difficult to think clearly about
emptiness or trying to go through the
death process or something like that so
the Longmen service in those moments
just say the name of your refuge it's
okay
se llama llama llama okay say your Namas
name say Buddha just say your teacher's
name if you can you can do a mantra
Mama's name mantra you can say ohm and
then if the llamas name is John Brady
didn't say um John Brady awful because
you're too scared to think of anything
else you can say the whole mantra
ultimate refuge mantra phone John Brady
Yahoo I'm falling down my airplanes
falling down I'm doing burning our own
John Belle Yolo it means help me John
Brady it's not your route teacher okay
well you can use your own teacher's name
okay so um see your teacher's name
ah okay if the plane is really falling
down you probably won't be able to
remember the mantra
so the lamrim says just say your mama's
name John John John John okay so in this
meditation
you just practice calling your llamas
names when you're in very serious danger
and you too
terrified or you're too sad to remember
anything else or think about anything
else just say their name John cha-cha
then you hit the ground okay with your
llamas name on your lips
so practice in your mind now remember
some situation like that and visualize
yourself just repeating your llamas
names as you die or as something
terrible happens clear we'll stay here
for a few minutes
and please come back to your breath deep
exhale
check with your mama in your heart and
then bring your mind back to this room
you can open your eyes take a stretch
what's the meditation Khan
[Music]
in moments of here in time okay
in moments of fear and pain number
fourteen okay yeah yeah and then it says
even just the words okay so this lineage
Diamond Mountain lineage okay our
lineage know when you call that Neil
some copying then is okay we are neo
total copying we're very big on the
meaning of things and we don't we're
trying not to do meaningless rituals you
know go to the temple waive incense and
you're going to go to to she to heaven
you know we're trying not to encourage
people to do things that they don't
understand or that are not going to help
them very much but there are exceptions
okay if you really believe in your root
Lama if you really have a proper
relationship with your heart teacher
whether it's a living person whether
it's a Buddha who lived a thousand years
ago whether it's someone you haven't met
yet but you can imagine them okay either
one the power of your heart teacher is
so big that if you just say their name
when you're having extreme troubles like
about to hit the ground in an airplane
or about the diamas
scorpion sting it's okay it works okay
because of the power of the your Lama
name is more powerful than Buddha okay
so it's okay in this meditation
you're going to practice getting hit by
a car or practice your airplane falling
down or practice I don't know
you know someone cheats a gun I had that
happen to me once this guy was following
me too close and I put my brakes on and
then he got angry and he followed me and
I finally I turned the corner and I
stopped and he came up next to me and he
shot a gun at me and I felt that powder
hit my face and it went through the
windows you know and it missed me you
know then if something like that happens
to you you know just something happens
and you get shot then llamas name died
okay that's the best you can do and it's
and it's good it's sufficient got it
so let's practice during the three days
okay what I'm going to do if someone
like if they if they just come up to me
and shoot me in the head then you should
have something ready right it happens
weird stuff happens do you remember Tom
Kiley no he's brought Daniel could his
brother someone in the East Village
came up to him and punch him in the face
as hard as he could just walking down
just let him stay boy and he he just
fell on the ground he's bleeding and
he's like well you know then you can say
so medication number 14 is emergency box
you know push the button
promise me that's all okay Thomas name
huh say again yeah yeah
huh my what is my sumathi Madra you can
take Tamaki
Sumati second is enmity okay all right
meditation 15 okay
what time we stop this guy okay I'll
give you a break after this one okay
we're going to get to this in alarm room
after the retreat okay but meditation 15
when I was in Thailand you know and we
gave everybody message bow and refuge
name then people get all excited you
know and they running around with their
new name and they're showing everybody
you know I have a new name
mine's cooler than yours you know he
gave he gave me this one special I'm not
like you you know and everybody start
wearing you can see in the Beijing
Airport you know suddenly everyone's
wearing these rosaries like 10 years ago
nobody now even the business guys are
wearing these rosaries and yoga teachers
like to do that I noticed when I go to
yoga they're all wearing rosary on the
wrong hand the right hand you always
wear it on your left hand because then
you can debate you know but uh so it
means people like to once they take
refuge or something
they like to use the akuto mo the the
cute little Dharma things you know look
I have beads my beads have turquoise on
them you know or I have crystal you have
wood you know or I have gold on my beads
but you yours are just metal you know I
have my my I have a refuge name and you
don't
you know it means that outer things that
are associated with spirituality and
people like them
some people wear religious clothes you
know like red clothes or white clothes
or black clothes and they get very
attached to them you know I have I have
there's a Geisha
Kumgang vest
it has a yellow stripe on it here you
know and in the monastery it's very
important you know if you have - yellow
stripes here everyone's like all getting
on geishas are you know I refused to
wear this you never saw me wear it I
have one but it's too small it was made
for Tibetans anyway and people get very
attached to it you know if you wear it
and you also in the tantric college you
get a special one and if you wear it
when you're not supposed to wear it
everyone gets upset you know you're not
supposed to wear that you know so what I
like about the Neo told copy and lineage
that we have the Newton copper minis
that we have is we are not very big on
these outer you know signs like I have
yellow stripe you don't have yellow
story you know I have llama hat you know
how a llama had you know I like it that
we are disguised as someone who owns a
cosmetics company in Singapore you know
like everybody thinks I'm just normal
person you know and I think that's very
healthy we don't have a hierarchy we
don't have Big Momma little big llama
big little llama you know really have
this thing you know and we don't have
people running and so you you shouldn't
do like this you should put your fingers
inside or you're a bad person you know I
like it that we don't have all this
silly things you know I'm happy we don't
have these things okay we we're working
on the inside to try to be a nice person
okay so meditation number 15 is to think
about that you know
am i attached to you know everybody sees
my beads and they know I'm a spiritual
person in ours you know am I trying to
impress people with my Tibetan grammar
skills like guessing Michael does you
know this outer thing okay it's not an
inner thing
look how much scripture I can quote you
know look how many words I can look up
in John's database you know who could
find that story that I told you this
morning these are all out of things okay
so what he's talking about are the outer
signs of taking refuge okay beads name
special hats you know
outer science that you took refuge and
and what he says is stick to the what's
it's a second husband second husband
refuge okay nobody knows you're doing it
okay
you're like oh this person irritate me
oh wait it's like second husband come
from me you know there's a joke at
Diamond Mountain there's a joke somebody
came from another place they came to
Diamond Mountain they said I can't
believe it
what everybody I meet
so stupid I'm surrounded by stupid
people then the old diamond mountain
people go okay yeah take a real refuse
okay and nobody knows if you took
graffiti or not okay
you understand emptiness and it's very
quiet and nobody can prove it
people come to me all the time I think I
saw emptiness I said okay tell me what
it's like I saw a green light yellow
I'll forget it you want to hear a real
conversation are you a conversation I
think I saw your doing I said no okay
one of the experience one of the
qualities of seeing emptiness is
directly is that you are sure you did it
nobody you don't have to ask anybody
okay and and the whole world can tell
you you didn't and you don't care you
know it's the big big big Lamas can say
you didn't and you say ok I didn't but I
did
yes not only you know and and you know
for sure so if you're not sure you did
it when you do you do when you do you
know and it doesn't matter what anyone
says you you know the world can blow up
and you don't care I saw it I know tell
me anything I don't care you know okay
so if you have to ask you dude all right
all right
sixteen
then I promised your break 4:30 its 427
meditation 16 by the way when we will go
through the schedule after the break and
your instructions say group 1 meditation
group 2 meditations day we have to split
them up ok number 16 it's very very
useful as you die to take refuge ok it's
similar to the falling down in the
airplane ok but if you can just remember
your Lamas Ming as you go through the
red light the wide light the black the
Mirage the the tidal wave the mountains
falling down ok
when you see it start the hallucinations
they're called standard hallucinations
they come to everyone who dies bugs
rabbits fish humans when you see them
start start saying your mama's name you
know if you can try to remember the
sacrifice Muskoka if you can just say
lungs move ok ok alright so that the
lamb rim when I teach you that from the
book it will say just if your llamas
name is on your lips when you die you're
doing ok
you'll be ok ok yeah
I would say personally okay this is just
my personal idea I believe that if you
have a good relationship with your heart
Lama and you say their name when you die
you cannot go to a lower room I would
say that okay minimum okay yeah I would
go to Lamas name at the back up and try
to get emptiness in there okay but you
know I've been in those situations and
and you're so scared all you can do is
the lamas need you to be honest
this idea of Pau that in the moment of
death you can suddenly cancel all the
all the sixty five years of bad deeds
it's not possible it's unlikely that you
will suddenly change at the moment of
death the habits that you've built up
your whole life it's unlikely galoop a
tradition so comp a tradition don't
don't count on it okay you're going to
be too scared you're going to be
hallucinating heavy it's as if you're
very drunk
extremely jump oh you're in the middle
of a bad dream it's a thing you can't
you don't have the capacity to go oh ho
oh yeah step number six you know it's
not going to happen okay so take care of
it now real power means take care of it
now you know understand emptiness now
while your mind is clear and don't wait
till your mind is to almost unclear it's
been in your whole life okay because
you're not going to be able to remember
anything okay
alright then I think I'll tell you a
story I wasn't going to do it but I'll
tell you a story
after the break okay
but it's about a person who maybe ice
how many people going to Indonesia how
many people thinking to go to Indonesia
yeah I'll tell you in Indonesia now if I
tell you now I don't have anything to
tell you in Indonesia you can listen to
the knowledgebase afterwards ok have a
break have a break we have to stay stick
on this subject
ok ok I'll tell you I gotta find it okay
take a break I'll find it before you
come back okay I'm going to tell you
Perl lady's story okay
it's called this story of Perl lady the
pearl pearl lady pearl Jew Julianne
okay pearl lady and it's just Dharma
location time it has no relevance to
anything okay and we should do it in
Indonesia but I was excited I found this
story in where were we shopping in
Taiwan in a coffee shop this is the
third story of how the Wheel of Life was
painted okay cool so to learn all the
stories you have to come to Buddha
Buddha in the Newseum scarf I'm going to
send you a photo
next our team there who's the gong is
leading the team's the photo team they
just found the right part of Buddha
Buddha it took us a couple months and to
gunk on the right place and I'll show
you this photo that they took okay so we
know where to go when we go there we can
climb up the mountain and I can teach
you the real life from the carvings okay
so this is another story of how the real
life was painted but it includes the
idea that if you're your Lamas name is
on your lips when you die things go
pretty well okay so this is called a
lengthy what's a ling Jie
yeah it's a it's a it's a negative event
that happened during the Buddhist life
that necessitated making a new rule okay
like originally it wasn't against the
rules to drink alcohol in Buddhism but
then a monk got drunk and did some bad
things so Buddha said okay from today
there's a new rule Buddhist can't drink
alcohol okay like that then those
stories negative stories are called
lanky okay here's the lanky
it is a lanky this is the length shape
for a nun's vow not to argue with each
other okay okay this comes from the nuns
vows this comes from the deny of us to
part for nuns okay sir okay okay let's
efendim Kundalini what is the legacy for
not arguing Tombo circa May
the other day to Selma so Buddha was
staying in a garden called Nevada Nagano
does a special country children dekhi in
India shock come the day cachaça develop
edema they docked on the day Howard
should do some to home base Buddha was
being very successful pushing people
into the director section emptiness okay
in that garden but I'd like to hang out
in gardens okay the diamond color Center
is also spoken in a garden right they'll
actually the tower to do some - all day
then people began to he got those garden
lectures became very popular term the
day he can talk to shadow and Buddha
would just non-stop dermatitis okay
gavel Saitama young shark our dark
corner and the king suddhodana who's
that Buddhist father came to those
lectures also he got turned on by his
sons teachings okay
he and his wife do seems to me the
authority to talk to Don work on things
they used to walk to the garden to hear
him do shanty much on the deck okay I'll
talk to the meeting sorry Salem Mohamed
um seed Sigma maybe table to shaping
[Music]
started to teach Dharma and people were
coming like these two honey something
like that
okay I'm just giving you a quick point
translation okay did I can now Richard
Schiff Allah Mickey wall beneath me
Germany enter the Dharma was so sweet
like honey that people were like that
and they didn't even have time to blink
okay then a gavel said some Allah so
Virginia man man don't were done then
the king the Buddhist father pseudo
Donna and all his friends
went back home in the evening after the
teaching shock in Ming Cheng Chi there
was a person in the Shakya people called
Mahanama and I believe he was one of the
five the four tiger cubs okay I think
he's one of the five first disciples of
Buddha
okay Kim D Tina he went home he sent a
Mahal
where did you hear that yeah it's in
your budget gimme prayer grace right mo
homies ha ha
we're so lucky ok so he went home and
said emmawho that expression is 2,000
years old two and a half thousand feet
on a mohawk he went home he said to his
wife Emma whole Sangha should get a
second to a new target gibecute oh I
must have some good karma seeds look at
these lectures were getting in the
garden you know whoa ha okay hey chill
man Kiba Papa said the chillin then his
wife said why you say Emma home you know
what happened he said hitting jump today
to shape a so Jackie I told Emma kept a
chill with chipper cattle buddha was
teaching all day and thousands of people
got you know huge spiritual results it's
amazing
it must be my good seed and then his
wife said it's not mine it ain't mine
not my good seeds catch our ladies ever
jebediah in Malacca Laurens not money
good seeds then he said they teacher
then he got upset he said why why do you
say such an unpleasant thing you know
she said getting them to church on the
day she came to chew me the Buddha came
to this world to teach males who make it
him lame he didn't come from women
chief she's pissed off yes they may but
they gave my surgery he said oh no don't
say that
okay turn the day nice and ten times a
table Temba buddha wants to help all
living beings okay Jason tell young
keiki I can't thank you why don't you
ladies organize a teaching you know come
get a dime a teaching from Lord Buddha
you know he likes everybody
you know father darkness a key member
kwrona tumba de la ceiba Shoob a doctor
from exciting arch Indian to Montana so
the ladies had a meeting all the Shakya
clan ladies had a meeting and they said
yeah let's go ask beautiful Dharma
teachings just ladies only money me Mara
and the guy the husband said why ladies
only she said you know we feel
embarrassed in front of men's you know
we can't let our hair down you know we
can't feel we natural we just want
ladies there okay can we have a teaching
like that doctor from exciting on each
Indian in Montana des Dames hot dog
Minato Jinyan dark chocolate Road
Chilean punana - oh I have a suggestion
she said you men go in the morning
before noon and then us ladies will have
our Dharma teaching in the afternoon
okay they named in Changi some Pataki
galvo said Tamela Mann I remember then
her husband said he thought it was a
good idea but he thought it's a little
disrespectful to ask the King Buddhist
father can we have a girls-only
afternoon because he's not a girl okay
Kagan Dhamma Tamela Toulon yummy big
mature then he thought it's more
appropriate if I asked the King's wife
okay I don't think it's Lord Buddha's
mother at this point I think she died or
something it's a long story
I'll ask her permission then the wife
can always convince the husband what to
do
then a cake Adama - my sake - Melania
coordination between young children so
they made the arrangement and 500 wives
and women of the shockula people walked
through the Negro the garden they say
chuckling tinker to magenta Yankee
Germany did not intend it to some of
them then the women who went to the
garden said you know if we're going to
go to teaching by Lord Buddha we should
dress up we should wear our best sunny
you know and all of our pearls and you
know gold and okay we should look nice
Kennedy dissenting some additional
sanction shipment of gent on Gigi Amina
and all the ladies dressed up with
others silk and jewels country of dejar
de madera dark
eutrophic Shepherd said on demagoguery
Tommy Ananda was there okay he was
allowed the monks were allowed to stay
the Shakya husband had to stay home but
Ananda was looking around at the monks
and some of them were like
okay then he thought to himself some of
these months are not advanced enough to
be around a bunch of beautiful ladies he
thought to himself like that you know
these ladies are too hot Simo Kiki yogi
Kyung
Ian's a Pathan this time again time
taking him to Dartmouth day you know
then he he told the ladies I think you
shouldn't dress up so much when you come
to the teaching because it's bad for the
young monks who are not experienced you
know
Thank You Sheena tortured you don t need
Digital Domain you know frankly speaking
not all of our monks are free of desire
okay there's some are young they're not
very experienced okay she Jordan was
arguing again Tonya topic poked a then
the women immediately understood and
they decided to take off their jewelry
pokemon schumer kuma-chan
she's our genomic data center coma then
there was a young lady who was a servant
girl and she had come along with them to
like serve them drinks and things like
that so they said here take our jewelry
back to the houses you know they asked
her you you take the pearls and things
put them in our house okay
children landing on burgundy rocking
chuchita they can kill me long so then
she took all the jewelry and went back
to the village
okay 10800 editorship in a shocking
motion Amish church ever turn on me
gonna open moot a case Amidala chakra
yonder yonder toshing lop account normal
then Buddha started to teach but there
was one young lady wife of some buddy
and she was too proud to send back her
pearls
so she still wear her pearls and then
she like this and then Buddhist teaching
you know and then she's like she just
distracted by her pearls okay
and she didn't send her pearls back home
then hm the big Amitabh Bachchan I am
and can Mohammed Amin change to mission
Ahmadi and the Buddha thought I should
teach about death meditation and this
lady will stop looking at her pearls
you know so he taught death meditation
then she's like she didn't hear it
[Music]
got it then a Mahanama wife right the
one who asked for the teachings she
thought I have to get this lady to stop
looking at her pearls then she had an
idea
I will send a servant girl back to my
house to bring my big pearl and I will
put them on and then this lady would
stop looking at her pearls because those
are cheap and mine are expensive okay
then she won't be distracted so she
asked the servant girl you know I
changed my name my mind go home bring
back my proof and let me say mother chop
up Hong Jinyoung something the pearls by
the way if you care it wasn't a necklace
exactly
it's called samode Oh similar is like
when you go to a big party expensive
dress and you wear a long dress and then
you have a small vest it stops here just
covered here that's called sama dose and
it's made of pearls okay so she said go
back and get my scimitar
tell me dear Jamie Thomas even a young
ddungi similar to China Jana Jana Donna
big held a dodgy sama dama dama if this
girl's is my scimitar they diverted a
metal gear on the under she will forget
her pearls and she will start listening
to the Buddha so she sent a servant girl
back to the house duccini become a
bikini Yellen young do some so the
servant girl walking back to the home
started to think about it
a Mahal but this is a upset mo mo ho chi
leadership like Jim Knox a Tony
everybody else gets to listen to the
Dharma and I'm running back and forth
with pearls you know they're guilty
courage a to be a servant in these times
in India is not fun a lien on the Megan
tender sinkage of member chengengxin but
do me among machine you want it it's not
fun to be a servant it's a lot of pain
everyone's bossing you around all the
time and I don't have a good income all
of this is because I didn't hear Dharma
in the past and now I don't get here
Dharma again and I'm just going to be
like this okay I want to listen to the
Dharma shame ever done something they
could go but beyond once I'm gay like
chocolate chip a sheet day then the
Buddha was reading her mind okay as
she's walking and take to a quarter I
give away you watch on yummy
then he saw her life is not going to be
very long she's not going to live very
much due to get sick so chipper
Tiktaalik cheated Chino then he wrote a
verse on a tree by magic on the bark of
a tree you know this white tree when I
call that birch tree you before paper
they used to use this for writing
a white tree skin right on that she's
walking right and he wrote it magic from
the teaching place okay with his
meditation Kevin um the debugger all
things which are born dies game a saying
I referred to you should understand your
life Menten Duke they kill onion you
should try to do some good comma not
docking me ship a little I give you this
private teaching on the tree part okay
then she's like wow she's so happy you
know she takes a tree bark off you know
and she's walking to get that some of
those and she's like wow duder wrote me
my own home you know I'm really special
you know and she kept reading this verse
you know to herself then she ran into
her cow and it kicked her and she died
on the road she's playing a boom dead
okay like that just die like that okay
but she was she had Buddhist name on her
her lives
okay that's why we're reading this story
okay she had Buddha's name on her mouth
when she got kicked and and she died
with Buddha's name from a day i'm gonig
situated darshan sunday attention to
some way say to and a key tool above me
non-discriminatory if you care the cow
was pregnant I don't know why they say
that but okay
based on gay attention to to induce
achiever because she died with the
Buddhist name on her lips she was born
as the princess of Sri Lanka long-case
day Tom dong say thirty booty to chop up
a minion mu T Masato and because she had
the pearls in her hands the day she was
born
pearl fell from the sky in Sri Lanka
the whole country okay pearls so the her
mom and dad the king and queen of Sri
Lanka they were saying maybe we should
call her pearl girl so they named her
program pearl they named her pearl okay
dia nation do Shing Shing nine Yin do
you paid so much gasoline do too chambo
Shan together sugar de Longhi two single
in English you know then some
businessmen merchants were in a boat off
the coast of what I called Malabar Coast
west southwest India and they got caught
in a windstorm
and it pushed them to Sri Lanka okay
they are from a place called travesty
what sure masti
it's where Lord Buddha talked to diamond
cutters okay they happened to be from
strumice li na gave up another million
women then they landed in sri lanka they
started to do some business and they
rented an apartment next to the palace
of the king
damn it Tony Liang shade on gentlemen on
antenna and we made a minister chaplain
to the city of the thermometer and every
night the business guys merchants they
used to get together and read suture out
loud like king hunting or singeing and
they will sing the Sutra Sabich own
courses such as a common colleges or
something if usually they start to sing
it okay then a pearl lady was in the
palace and she heard this beautiful song
wow I never heard this this is such a
beautiful song you know did she said
those musicians are really good then she
asked her father can you invite these
foreign musicians to sing in the palace
you know sorry he has a lot of money and
he asked the businessmen you guys you
must be a rock'n'roll band or something
can you come to the palace and sing for
us you know okay telling anything
addition to so then they they said look
we're not singers we're businessmen but
every night together we sing the jingle
jingle ching ching it's a prayer and she
said well what's the prayer about they
said it's to Buddha and when she heard
the word Buddha she said she like
something happened to her she saw Buddha
you know some past life memory she saw
Nina's dead Aki sanitary ending of Allah
she'd day then they started to tell her
how cool is Buddha this guy named Buddha
okay summer
then they told his whole story okay how
he was a prince how he got enlightened
you know and she was she heard the whole
story
mm-hmm then she she then the evening was
finished and she said when you guys are
ready to go home
can you come see me because I want to
send this guy a message okay then I
called Jonathan Demme accountability Nia
Chickasaw and she gave them
she wrote a message to the Buddha and
it's a poem okay Lama in Vance on me
ChaCha
kid on my way jiggling moon detail
tropical malappuram duck tells a beauty
Mopani amid our low gods and humans both
here you are free of this of the fierce
of person gasps troublesome American dog
everybody in the world has heard of you
transid oozing liver Nia Madonna can you
grant me nectar okay can you give me
nectar of deathlessness please then a
samba de da ki duniya ke Tony dinner
program they went back to shrawasti they
met Lord Buddha and they gave him the
note god Sara somebody kingdom jingling
jingle a ling you don't acknowledge
changing and buddha said what when you
go back to Sri Lanka can you take a
message
kid are darker Serena and they said yeah
sure Taranaki
and me Nikki quits a remote eBay in the
meantime Lord Buddha had a portrait made
of himself
okay to send to her
painting okay de Alta similar caps of
God on loving Kim Yuna and then below at
the bottom part of the portrait he drew
the Wheel of Life
okay it's a strange message to send to
someone you just met
okay here's my picture and here's the
Wheel of Life
okay two millimeter Myrna toponym you're
not I'm Tina going to six chamber and he
wrote that famous verse right salvage a
senior Johnson attended a good job Tom
became Alan kitchen didn't I tell you so
much our country patron are you pay to
the dealer
children were killer Corey what's up me
did not tell me qu partial he wrote
these two verses very famous painting
routine mabini Jian shade some dollar
may be done then she got the message and
the painting and she opened it up and
she asked a businessman what is this
what's this thing then they told her
what the painting abound
okay and who's this guy's picture okay
then she went to her bedroom and she
recited the 12 banks three times and
before she finished the third time she
saw emptiness okay cool son game ring
then she said a very famous poem
Hungarian Egyptian dear shut up Kenny me
jungle Buddha you live far away I never
met you but you have opened my eyes
Kagamine agenda wahrman Kagura
you are the supreme physician you are
the greatest doctor in the world son
getting nauseous Hindu darling Sulochana
to you ripped out my wrong idea about
the world okay three generativity and
mega-deal each other I bow down to the
Great Physician the great doctor
tipping somebody like the kingdom during
a dollar key she did hockey camp attack
so she said can you take this pop back
to Lord Buddha okay because she reached
aiya okay Boutique maiden Allah dancing
Tony Bishara chocolate again switching
media channel Middle Kingdom then she
sent back
Lord Buddha her best wishes and Gary
Shannon Chamba Della Femina then she
said because you became my teacher okay
darksome daniela chosen denied alaikum I
will never again have to go to the hell
realms I will never again be an animal I
will never again be a hungry spirit in
fact I will never be a human or a demon
I'm free from the wheel Chima non-target
away
you have when you cover sorry
the ocean of blood and tears has dried
up okay I have crossed the mountains of
skeletons I have destroyed the mountain
of wrong views with my Raja my diamond
because of your teachings okay and I
reached aiya
because of you okay
Simba delta o mundo Kyoto I I crossed
the ocean across the ocean now I will
always take refuge in Buddha Dharma
Sangha and can you ask him if he will
give me my lifetime vows laymen vows can
I have those vows then she packed up
three boxes of pearls seed pearls are
coming back and she made three Jessop
rose and she said to the merchants give
these to the Buddha Dharma and Sangha
when you get home okay one box for each
okay and they went back home and they
offered the three boxes to Lord Buddha
then Lord Buddha said to Ananda Ananda
okay
do remember that irritating servant girl
who was unhappy about carrying pearls
back and forth
and got kicked by the cow and he said
yeah I remember her
that was very sad then he said well as
she was dying she had my name on her
lips so she was born as the princesses
of Sri Lanka and I sent her in the wheel
of life and because of that she saw
emptiness directly okay and then
anonymous like wow that's super cool he
was really happy then he said what do
you want me to do with the three boxes
of pearls then Buddha said well the part
that she dedicated to the Buddha is for
me so I want you to glue them to the
wall of the temple you know put them on
the walls of the temple so the temples
beautiful all pearls that's what you can
do with mine and the box that was for
the Dharma jewel you have to give to
people who are practicing Dhamma okay
and the part that was for the Sangha you
can give that box to the Sangha okay
to make sure you put Calcutta but they
change them because like the large
system enough they tame unzipping them
don't touch anything and then
[Music]
so there were models who specialize in
Sutra teachings and there were monks who
specialize in vinaya teaching and there
were monks who specialized in abhidhamma
teaching guess what happened each one
said we get the box okay the other dummy
guy said we should get the bark the
Vinaya guy said we should get the box
okay
the sutra god said we should get the box
okay and then they started to argue and
that's the end of the story no event
buddha said don't fight over you know
physical things that that month
shouldn't monks and nuns shouldn't argue
with each other and that's the legacy
you see the whole story is not about the
wheel of life and it's not about 12
links and it's not even about you know
it's about not arguing cuz then Buddha
had to make a rule monks and nuns and
argue with each other okay got it okay
now
that's the short version
I believe it's teacher repurchase
summary okay
and there's a 200 page long version
which I didn't do
okay that's like the 10 page version
there's a much longer version very
beautiful 200 pages long
I'm very beautiful anyway and that's
another teaching of The Wheel of Life
and he explains that we look like you
know okay maybe we do it in butter
butter you have to tell me who is it
business Oh
so Jenny we have two minutes left
Jenny's going to make an announcement so
I put on the screen already okay this is
a Buddhahood Oh rich free so right now
actually is 1500 but it's on the class
everybody register we still keep
everybody special price Ripa price only
bought this class so we hope everybody
can go learn from Joshua in the Buddha
Buddha retreat
okay thank you everybody crush the
charge okay the teaching is free okay
the hotel takes the money and we got a
nice hotel because we want to it's a
five-star hotel and it's a two-hour
flight from Singapore it's about a two
and a half hours from China
okay so easy you go to Jakarta and you
take another flight to joke the cover
okay all right then oh yeah
this photo was taken two days ago by our
teams in borobudur and this is one of
the stories and so we identified
the carvings about the wheelers life so
the the whole will climb up the mountain
and I'll teach you the Wheel of Life
some of their carvings okay it's very
beautiful and to gun and we're doing the
book with a very famous German
photographer burn coal who's a famous
businessman he was the entrepreneur of
the year he started internet business in
Germany and we did a program together
and he's a very famous photographer so
we're trying to finish a book before
that for you but I don't know if I'll
have time we're trying okay